<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thoughts on Pratik Kokil</title>
    <link>https://notreallypk.github.io/tags/thoughts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thoughts on Pratik Kokil</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://notreallypk.github.io/tags/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Logs &#39;25</title>
      <link>https://notreallypk.github.io/writings/logs25/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://notreallypk.github.io/writings/logs25/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oct 25 &amp;lsquo;25.&lt;/strong&gt; Been reading the series &lt;a href=&#34;https://notreallypk.github.io/refs/exiting-modernity.pdf&#34;&gt;Exiting Modernity&lt;/a&gt; by Meta-Nomad.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Oct 14 &amp;lsquo;25.&lt;/strong&gt;  Read a decent &lt;a href=&#34;https://archive.is/o2BFF&#34;&gt;write up&lt;/a&gt; on Alec Radford. For anyone who know&amp;rsquo;s the field, the man is a prolific researcher. His work spans Audio (Generative Audio), Speech (Whisper) , Text (GPT1, GPT2) to Vision (CLIP).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m still not up to do much work today. So, I have instead been watching a series of videos on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ajFXykT9Joo&#34;&gt;Secret History&lt;/a&gt; by the Predictive History YouTube channel. I especially liked the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hk_yhi3-prw&#34;&gt;death by bureaucracy&lt;/a&gt; which ties in to the theme of various sources I have been reading from (longer rant incoming soon). To start off, watch &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oimFqwQgR3g&#34;&gt;Poverty Inc.&lt;/a&gt;; you will see how majority of the aid actually goes towards servicing the bureaucracy that exists to get the aid. Although quite informal, read to get a gist of unproductive people read Geohot&amp;rsquo;s post &lt;a href=&#34;https://geohot.github.io/blog/jekyll/update/2025/09/01/you-will-blame-the-wrong-people.html&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sounds Of Silence</title>
      <link>https://notreallypk.github.io/writings/2022-3-12-sounds-of-silence/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://notreallypk.github.io/writings/2022-3-12-sounds-of-silence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;i&#34;&gt;I.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“What does silence sound like?” That is not the question I began my day with. I woke up with a cool breeze hitting my body, it is a summer morning - at the backdrop of a warm atmosphere, the fan was running at full speed.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I checked the time - it was 6:45 AM. it was a pleasant surprise, I slept at 12:00 AM and half expecting myself to wake up early, I had an alarm for 7:15 AM. It is a different feeling all together for me - when it feels like I’m ahead of the day, as opposed to playing catch up throughout the day - why is it so, maybe for some other time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Ode to the Internet</title>
      <link>https://notreallypk.github.io/writings/2022-1-30-the_internet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://notreallypk.github.io/writings/2022-1-30-the_internet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;i&#34;&gt;I.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;On August 15, 1995, Indians woke up to the tariff plan of a new sort of communication service. They could buy dial-up internet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At Rs 15,000 a year, it was not quite something the average Indian could afford then.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was still a young kid when I had a glimpse of the Internet&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. The old dial-up connection tones, the slow speeds and hefty charges levied.  But I was part of the generation that grew up with it’s evolving use cases. From simple search back then to entire generations who experience banking online and now even - &lt;a href=&#34;https://minto.ai/digital-transformation-series-what-are-we-learning-from-our-ongoing-deployments/&#34;&gt;digital factories&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
